aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Grounded Fire Dagwon
파이어 다그온 발진 불가
Space Electronic Man Electron Seijin
Appears
우주 전인 일렉트론 성인 등장
It's not good! I'm gonna be late!
큰일이구만!
이대로 가다간 지각이라구!
Good!
좋았어!
Wh- what the?!
엇! 뭐야?!
Nice try, but this isn't making me late for school!
이정도 일로 지각할 것 같냐!
No way... I won't be able to make it!
말도안돼... 이래선 제 때 갈 수 없겠어
I see! I'm here, and if I go straight by going through non-roads...
그렇군, 지금 있는 곳은 여기고 이렇게 일직선으로 길 아닌 길을 나아가다 보면...
2 minutes will do! Heh, I'm a genius!
2분이면 도착할 수 있어! 훗, 천재구만 나는
Let's go!
가자!
Good morning!
안녕하세요~
Hey, you!
요놈아~!
DANGER
Do not enter!
위험
출입금지!
Something's not right...
이상한데?
This factory is supposed to be closed...
이 공장은 이제 폐쇄됐을텐데...
What was that?!
뭐지, 지금 그건?!
Th- that's an alien!
저, 저건 우주인?!
Now of all time! What should I do?
하필이면 이런 때에...
어떻게 하지?
I'm paralyzed! You dared to attack me!
마비됐다! 크윽...
잘도 공격했겠다!
I'll send you to hell in 30 seconds!
30초 안에 보내주마!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Elbow Claw!
엘보 클로!
I did it!
해치웠다!
That didn't make a scratch on that guy?!
통하지 않는 건가, 이녀석?!
Shoulder Burn!
숄더 번!
Did it work?
해치웠나?
It was kinda boring...
어째 싱거운 녀석인걸
Oh, no! I'm completely late!
엇, 큰일이다!
완전히 지각이구만, 이거
It's bad! The class must've already already started!
이런~ 벌써 수업 시작했잖아
I wonder if I can just go over...
어떻게 잘 넘어갈 수 없으려나?
You might fool other teachers, but you're not fooling the eye of Haruka Ijuuin.
다른 선생님들은 속일 수 있어도 이 이쥬인 하루카의 눈은 속일 수 없다네
You are late.
자네는 지각이군
He's the worst one to be discovered to... How unlucky I am.
가장 들키기 싫은 녀석에게 들켜버렸구만, 참 운도 없지
Cut the chatter and get down!
잔말 말게! 어서 내려오게나
Yeah.
예이~
-Give me your student book.
-Yeah, yeah.
-학생 수첩
-예 예~
One reply is enough.
대답은 한번으로 족하네
Yeah~
네~
Huh? I should have it inside here...
어레? 이상하네 여기 넣어두었을 텐데...
I cannot express how am I truly stifled at you.
정말 기가 막혀서 말도 안나오는군요
First, you were late and went over the wall,
지각을 해서 담을 넘더니만
and now you even threw away your student book and came to school.
이젠 학생수첩마저 어디다 갖다버리고 학교에 오다니
What kind of useless youth you're having!
도대체 이 얼마나 쓰잘데없는 청춘을 보내고 있는겐가 자네는?!
Hey! I attend school with a painful heart that I can't talk with someone else!
이봐요! 난 다른 사람에겐 말할 수 없는 괴로~운 마음으로 학교에 다니고 있다구요!
I'd like if you didn't talk as if it's useless.
쓰잘데없다는 말은 하지 말아줬으면 좋겠는데요...
Oh? A painful heart that you can't talk with someone else?
호오? 다른 사람에겐 말할 수 없는 괴로~운 마음이라고?!
Hmph! I guess you just overslept after doing some useless part time job!
흥! 어차피 하차~않은 아르바이트라도 하느라 늦잠 잔 거겠지!
That isn't true! The traffic light randomly changed from green to red,
아니라구요! 신호등이 파란불이 됐다가 빨간불이 됐다, 이상해져 버렸지
an accident happened in the crossroad, blocking me from going through, and I also had to fight against an alien!
건널목은 사고로 건널 수 없게 되었지 덤으로 우주인과도 싸워야 하지
That's why I was late! I can't do something about that!
그래서 지각한 거라구요!
할 수 없잖아요!
An alien?
우주~인?!
It seems that use definitely need the educational guidance of me, Haruka Ijuuin.
아무래도 자네에겐 이 이쥬인 하루카의 교육적 지도가 필요한 것 같군
Follow me to the staff's room!
교무실까지 따라오세요!
What are you doing to me?!
무슨 짓이예요!
Let me go!
놓으라구요!
No! I won't!
싫~어! 못놔!
The existence of students like you hinders the fate of our school!
자네같은 학생의 존재는 우리 학교의 존망과 관계된단 말이네!
What the hell are you blabbering about?!
무슨 귀신 씨나락 까먹는 소릴 하고 있는 거요?!
It's you who is blabbering! Follow me!
씨나락 까먹는 건 자네다! 따라오게!
-Let me go!        -Follow!
-놔요!
-따라오게!
I wonder what you people are doing.
지금 뭣들하는 겐가?
Principal?
교장 선생님?!
The fact is, this student was late, so...
실은 이 학생이 지각을 해서, 그 때문에...
Grandpa! Let me explain!
할아버지! 이건 말이예요
Daidouji.
다이도우지!
-Are you alright?
-Um, yeah...
-몸은 괜찮나?
-아, 예...
Oh, really? That's good to know.
그렇군, 그거 다행이군
Now, hurry up to and go. The class has already begun.
자 자, 어서 가게나
수업이 벌써 시작되었다네
Alright! Excuse me!
네, 네!
실례하겠습니다~
Principal, what was the meaning of that?
교장 선생님! 대체 무슨 짓을?
That student is...
저 학생은 말입니다!
-Vice principal?
-Yes?
-교감 선생님
-아, 네
Being healthy is the best!
건강이 최고! 랍니다
Hey! What were you gonna talk about?
여어~ 할 이야기란게 뭐냐?
I was just going to remind you once again.
다시 한 번 확인해 두려고 생각해서 말야
About what, Kai?
뭘 말야, 카이?
The fact that we are the Dagwon that protects the Earth...
우리들이 지구를 지키는 다그온이라는 사실은
isn't to be known.
발설해서는 안된다는 것 말이다
Huh? Did someone bragged about it?
얼레? 누가 떠벌렸냐?
Isn't that dangerous?
위험한거 아냐, 그거?
M- me?!
나, 나라고?!
Don't say stupid! I never said about that!
바보같은 소리 하지마! 난 발설한 적 없다구!
Are you going to use the fact that you're a Dagwon as an excuse for being late?
네놈은 다그온으로서 행동하는 것을 지각의 변명으로 둘러댈 셈이냐?
I just said I tried to stop the invasion of aliens, but never said anything about Dagwon!
난 우주인의 침략을 막으려 했다고 했을 뿐 다그온이란 말은 안 했다구!
Did an alien appear again?
또 우주인이 나타난 겁니까?
Huh? Really?
아? 정말이냐?
Don't worry. I took care of it in the place.
걱정하지마 그자리에서 내가 해치워 버렸으니까 말야
Listen, En. Do not forget that we are high school students, before being Dagwon.
알겠나, 엔? 우리들은 다그온이기 전에 한사람의 고등학생이라는 사실을 잊지 마라
Even if I want to forget, I can't.
잊고 싶어도 잊을 수 없다구
Keep in mind that your lighthearted disclosure might call a danger to this school, and of course including us.
네놈의 경솔한 발설은 우리들은 말할 것도 없이 이 학교에도 위험을 부를지 모른다는 것을 명심해라
Alright?
알겠나?
Shut up. Don't try to teach me as if you're someone great!
시끄러워! 하나하나 잘난듯이 설교하지 말라구!
You become emotional right away like that.
그렇게 바로 감정적이 되는 것
That also is your weakness. Fix that.
그것도 엔, 너의 결점이다. 고쳐라
I can't stand listening to you!
이자식, 가만히 못 듣겠구만!
I guess you didn't understand what I'm saying about.
내가 말하는 걸 이해하지 못한 것 같군
Shut up, you brat!
닥쳐, 이자식아!
You bastard! I'll throw you away!
이자식! 작살내주마!
That damned En!
엔 녀석...!
Do you think you can take me down with your distorted guts?
네놈의 비뚤어진 근성으로 날 쓰러뜨릴 수 있을거라고 생각하나?
Interesting. Let's finish this right here.
재미있군, 결판을 내주마!
Stop, you guys! What are you doing in my club room?!
잠깐, 너희들! 남의 부실에 멋대로 들어와서 무슨 짓들이야?!
Maria? What happened to your face?
마리아? 얼굴은 그래가지고 무슨 일이냐?
It's your fault!
너 때문이잖아!
Calm down, Ms. Maria. If you keep being angry, your pretty face will become ugly.
진정하세요, 마리아씨 자꾸 화내면 예쁜 얼굴이 흉해져요
Uh, sorry, I said nothing.
아, 아니.. 아무것도;;;
Really, you bastard always make troubles one after one.
정말, 하나부터 열까지 소란을 피우는 녀석이군, 네놈은...
What did you say, you-!
뭐라고, 이자식?!
Stop it!
그만두게나!
Vice principal?!
앗, 교감선생님?!
Is it you again? You're now dragging someone else and fighting?
또 자네인가? 이번엔 다른 학생을 끌어들여 싸움질을...!
Unforgivable! Definitely unforgivable!
용서못해! 절대 용서못해!
Follow me!
따라오게!
J- just a moment! That wasn't me! Uh...
자, 잠깐 기달려요;;
그건 제가 아니예요, 저기...
Just follow me!
됐으니까, 따라오게!
That's a misunderstanding! Hey, let me go!
잠깐, 오해라구요!
이봐요, 놓으라니까요
Hey, vice principal!
어이, 교감 선생님!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Principal's Room
교장실
I can't stand this anymore!
더이상 참을 수 없습니다!
If we let this student do as he want furthermore, he will affect our students in bad way.
이 이상 이 학생을 방치시켜 둔다면 다른 학생에게까지 악영향을 끼치게 됩니다
Principal, please make a decision.
교장 선생님, 결단을...
It can't be helped.
할 수 없군요
-Daidouji En, as a punishment for you...
-Yeah, as a punishment for you...
-다이도우지 엔, 자네에게 벌로..
-그래, 자네에게 벌로..
I'll make you do clean all the restrooms in the school for a week.
1주일간 교내 전체의 화장실 청소를 시키겠습니다
Right, one week of... What? Only a week?
그래, 일주일간...
에에? 일주일간?!
Huh?! Restroom cleaning?! Suspension is whole lot better!
에엑?! 화장실 청소?! 차라리 정학하는 편이 낫다구요!
P- principal! Only a week is too weak!
교, 교장 선생님! 단지 일주일 뿐이라니, 너무 무릅니다!
We must punish students like him severely!
이런 학생에겐 더욱 엄한 처벌을!
-Vice principal!
-Uh, yeah?
-교감 선생님
-네, 네?
-That's all.
-Alright...
-이상입니다
-네...
I understand. But on one condition.
알았습니다, 하지만 조건이 있습니다
What is it?
뭡니까?
During the week, if this student skips even for once, let me give him more pungent punishment.
그 일주일 사이에 이 학생이 한번이라도 빼먹거나 한다면 더욱 엄한 처벌을 내리겠습니다
Hm? Do you agree, Daidouji?
호오~ 어떻게 하겠나, 다이도우지?
Alright.
알았습니다
-That's how it is, vice principal.
-Got it!
-그럼 그렇게 하세요, 교감 선생님
-네!
Is this place En told us about?
엔이 말한 곳이 이곳인가?
There definitely are traces of fight.
확실히 싸운 흔적은 있군
Do you believe what En said?
엔의 말을 믿어주는 건가?
He has moral problems, but he never lies.
녀석은 도덕적으론 문제가 있지만, 거짓말은 하지 않아
Well, that's true.
뭐, 그렇지
Pretty female college students everywhere!
아름다운 여대생으로 가득하구만~
Be serious! We're about to gather new alien samples.
진지하게 좀 하세요! 또 새로운 우주인의 표본을 입수할 수 있을지도 모른다구요
Your youth is becoming friends with aliens.
너의 청춘은 우주인과 친구가 되는 것
My youth is becoming friends with female college students.
나의 청춘은 여대생 누님과 친구가 되는것
Leave me alone.
가만히 내버려 달라구
This humongous creature has suddenly appeared in a power plant.
이 거대 생물은 발전소에서 갑자기 나타났습니다
It is currently attacking the plant.
현재 발전소를 습격중입니다
What am I doing? A friend of justice, cleaning restrooms?
정의의 사자가 화장실 청소라니...
What are you murmuring? Clean it with all your heart.
뭘 그리 궁시렁대는 겁니까? 마음을 담아서 하나하나 깨끗하게 닦으세요
Yeah, yeah, of course.
네, 네~ 알았다구요
-One answer is enough!
-Sure~!
-대답은 한번!
-예~이!
Eat this!
받아랏!
What the-? It's not working at all!
뭐야, 끄떡 없잖아?!
The enemy is fully charged! It's going to counterattack if we don't do proper attacks!
상대는 완전히 충전된 상태입니다 어줍잖은 공격으론 반격당할 뿐입니다!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Armor!
다그 아머!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Wing!
다그 윙!
What the heck is En doing?!
엔 녀석은 어떻게 된거야?!
En is busy cleaning restrooms right now!
엔은 지금 한참 화장실 청소중입니다
You must be joking! A friend of justice can't fight, just because of restroom cleaning?!
말도 안돼! 정의의 사자가 화장실 청소 때문에 못온다는 거냐?!
It can't be helped. Let's combine and finish at once!
할 수 없다!
단숨에 합체해서 싸우자!
Roger!
라져!
Chaining Fusion!
중련합체(重連合體)!
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온!
Here we go!
간다!
Armor Buster!
아머 버스터!
Did we do it?
해치웠나?
What the-?!
아니?!
Hyper Crush!
하이퍼 크러쉬!
I can't do it anymore! Do I have to do this for a whole week?!
정말, 더이상 못해먹겠구만 이딴걸 앞으로 일주일간이나 하는건가
You still have to clean three more places. You're not going back until you finish.
아직 3곳이 남아있네
그게 끝나기 전까진 돌아갈 수 없다네
That guy...!
저녀석은?!
What are you doing, Liner Dagwon?!
뭘 하고 있는 거야, 라이너 다그온?!
What are you doing, Daidouji?!
뭘 하고 있는 겐가, 다이도우지?!
Move quicker!
좀 더 빨리 움직이라구!
It wouldn't change even if you shouted here!
자네가 떠벌여봤자 소용없잖는가?
You just do what you have to do, and that's enough.
자네는 자기 일을 하면 되는겁니다
But in this rate, they'll be done for!
하지만 이대론 저녀석들이 당한다구요!
What are you saying? Even if you go, nothing will change.
무슨 소린가? 당신이 간다고 해도 상황은 바뀌지 않아
Don't you know something that easy?
그런것도 모르는 겐가?
You are not getting this at all! If I don't go, they'll be...!
모르는건 당신이라구! 내가 가지 않는다면 저녀석들은...!
Are you alright, Liner Dagwon?
괜찮나, 라이너 다그온?!
-It's no good! Run away!
-Stop this!
-위험해! 도망쳐!
-그만 두게!
Let me go! ...please! Please let me go!
부탁이예요!
아니, 부탁드리겠습니다! 절 보내주세요!
What are you saying? Are you trying to run away?
무슨 소린가? 이런 때에 도망치려는 겐가?!
Teacher, I beg of you! Please let me go!
선생님 부탁드립니다
보내주세요!
Don't say stupid!
말도 안되는 소리 말게!
Please, vice principal! Let me go!
부탁드립니다! 교감 선생님!
제발 절 보내주세요!
Even if you do that, what's impossible is impossible! Stop that!
그런 짓을 해도 안되는 건 안된단 말이네! 작작 좀 하게!
Even if I beg you like this, won't it work at all?
이렇게 부탁해도 안된다는 겁니까...
Of course!
당연하네!
I don't care if I get suspended or withdrew anymore!
정학이든 퇴학이든 이판사판이다!
Stop it!
그만두세요!
Stop it, Daidouji.
그만두세요, 다이도우지
G- grandpa...
하, 할아버지...
P- principal!
교장 선생님!
Did you see? He showed his fist at me!
보셨죠?! 지금 저한테 주먹을 치켜세웠습니다!
It's a school violence!
교내 폭력입니다!
In this rate, my friends will... my friends will be done for!
이대론 동료가... 동료가 당하고 말아요!
That's why I must...
그러니까 전...
I must go!
전 가지 않으면 안돼요!
Please! Let me go!
부탁드립니다! 절 보내주세요!
Alright. When you're done with it, come back.
알았습니다, 볼일이 끝나면 돌아오세요
Yes! I will definitely come back!
네! 반드시 돌아오겠습니다!
Wh- what was that for, principal?! Do you even know what you just did?!
무, 무슨 짓입니까, 교장 선생님?! 당신이 무슨 짓을 했는지 알고 계신 겁니까?!
Yes, I do know.
네, 알고 있습니다
A youth is to be fiercely burning up!
청춘이란 뜨겁게 타오르는 것! 이랍니다
Stop it!
그만둬!
You bastard!
이자식!
En?!
엔?!
Sorry to make you wait!
기다리게 해서 미안하다, 얘들아!
Are you late again? You gotta fix that!
또 지각이냐?
어떻게든 좀 해 봐라!
Here I go! Prepare yourself!
간다, 각오해라!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)!
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온!
Fire Hold!
파이어 홀드!
Fire Blade!
파이어 블레이드!
What happened to him? He's cleaning restrooms without any grunt.
어떻게 된거냐, 저녀석? 성실하게 화장실 청소 따윌 해대고 말야
Really, he's became someone totally different.
글쎄요, 마치 딴사람 같아요
En, did you finally change?
엔, 드디어 개심(改心)했구나
I am happy.
난 기쁘다
What are you talking in sleep?
뭔 잠꼬대 같은 소리냐?
I'm just keeping the promise.
난 단지 약속을 지킬 뿐이라구
Promise?
약속?
Yeah, because he believed in me.
그래, 믿어 줬으니까 말야
If I betray the principal who let me go without asking anything at all, I'd be punished by heaven!
아무것도 물어보지 않고 보내준 교장 선생님을 배신했다간 천벌 받는다구
That's wrong! Your method of cleaning isn't perfect.
틀렸어! 그런 손놀림으론 완벽하다고 할 수 없어
Give it to me.
이리 줘봐
Look and learn. Like this!
잘 보라구
이렇게 하는 거다!
-Alright! Then leave the girls' restroom to me!
-Huh? Wait a moment!
-좋아! 그럼 여자 화장실은 나한테 맡기라구!
-에?! 잠깐만요!
-Stop! What are you doing, you pervert?!
-It's a misunderstanding, Maria!
-잠깐! 무슨 짓을 하는거야, 이 변태!
-오, 오해야! 마리아 씨!
I was just trying to make friends...
난 우정을 다지려고 생각해서...
Why do I have to make friend in restroom with Shin?!
어째서 내가 신과 화장실에서 우정을 다지지 않으면 안되는 거야?!
No, that's a misunderstanding too!
앗, 아니야! 그것도 오해라니까~
Ryu?
류?
I pay my debt.
빚은 갚는 성격이라서 말야
Really, nobody is frank.
정말, 모두 솔직하지 못하다니까요
You all...
너희들...
Hey, En! You do it properly too!
이봐, 엔!
네놈도 얼른 하라구!
Alright!
알았어!
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
tomaru koto nai MELODY
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
tooku kirameita
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
A mysterious Dagwon, Ryu Hashiba.
수수께끼의 다그온, 하시바 류
His true identity is even more obscure than aliens!
녀석의 정체는 우주인보다도 알 수가 없다구
But that Ryu and I are trapped into a trap of an alien and now only two of us are in the space of game!
그런데 그 류와 내가 우주인의 함정에 빠져서 게임 공간으로 단 둘이 들어갔어!
Damn, Fire En will have to be idle for a while!
크윽, 파이어 엔은 잠깐 타임이다!
I will leave this game upon your Merging Fusion form, Dag Shadow!
이 게임! 너의 융합합체 다그 섀도우에게 맡기겠어!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Game Over
다음회 용자지령 다그온
게임 오버
Do not die, Ryu!
죽지마라, 류!
Game Over
게임 오버